<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antonio Sberna</title>
    <link>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://AntonioSberna.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Antonio Sberna</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/media/icon_hu14779c9fd8200bd6f7905e79c1eadfc8_13109_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Antonio Sberna</title>
      <link>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new genetic algorithm-based framework for optimized design of steel-jacketing retrofitting in shear-critical and ductility-critical RC frame structures</title>
      <link>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/publication/ga-scdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/publication/ga-scdc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal seismic retrofitting of reinforced concrete buildings by steel-jacketing using a genetic algorithm-based framework</title>
      <link>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/publication/ga-sj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/publication/ga-sj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=center&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Publication&lt;/strong&gt;: Journal &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=center&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Publication&lt;/strong&gt;: in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/journal/engineering-structures&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineering Structure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; vol &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/journal/engineering-structures/vol/219/suppl/C&#34;&gt;219&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An new framework for the optimization of steel jacketing retrofitting interventions on RC columns is presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method can provide topological optimization (location) and amount of steel-jacketing reinforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The optimization process is based on a genetic algorithm handling a fiber-section model realized in OpenSees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feasibility individual solutions is controlled by the capacity/demand ratio resulting from pushover analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application of the method can effectively reduce retrofitting costs maintaining a specified safety level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The framework can be used by practitioners as a tool for sustainable retrofitting interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrofitting of existing reinforced concrete (RC) frame structures by steel angles and battens (steel-jacketing) is a commonly employed technique used to retrofit beams and columns against gravity and seismic loads. Steel-jacketing (SJ) effectively provides additional deformation and strength capacity to RC members but its application is associated with noticeable downtime of the building and non-negligible costs, depending on the amount of structural and non-structural manufacturing and materials. This paper presents an optimization framework aimed at the minimization of seismic retrofitting-related costs by an optimal placement (topological optimization) and amount of steel-jacketing reinforcement. In the proposed framework a 3D RC frame fiber-section model implemented in OpenSees is handled by a genetic algorithm routine that iterates reinforcement configurations to match the optimal solution. The feasibility of each solution is controlled by the outcomes of a static pushover analysis in the framework of N2 method. Results will provide optimized location and amount of steel-jacketing reinforcement, showing how effective and sustainable reduction of retrofitting costs is achievable maintaining a specified safety level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AntonioSberna.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
